Batt, Rosemary Gender and Global Change Program Files /4322
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Rosemary Batt Gender and Global Change Program Files
2003-2008
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Batt, Rosemary
Cornell University, Gender and Global Change Program
/4322
0.5 cubic feet
0.5 linear ft.
Case files, records (documents).
9218939
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 20, 2015
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 05, 2016
Biographical / Historical
Rosemary Batt is the Alice Hanson Cook Professor of Women and Work at the ILR School, Cornell University. She is a Professor in Human Resource Studies and International and Comparative Labor. She received her BA from Cornell University and her Ph.D. from the Sloan School of Management, Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Her research focuses on comparative international studies of management and employment relations, with particular attention to the impact of financialization on management and employment and the globalization and restructuring of service industries and its impact on low wage workers. She previously coordinated the Global Call Center Project/. She has written extensively on human resource practices and their effect on firm performance, the quality of jobs, and wage and employment outcomes.
Her work has appeared in such journals as the Academy of Management Journal, British Journal of Industrial Relations, the European Journal of Industrial Relations, Industrial and Labor Relations Review, Industrial Relations, International Journal of Human Resource Management, and Personnel Psychology. She is co-author of Private Equity at Work (2014) with Eileen Appelbaum; co-editor of the Oxford Handbook on Work and Organization and co-author of The New American Workplace: Transforming Work Systems in the United States, Cornell University Press.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4318: Rosemary Batt Call Center Research Materials /4322 AV: Rosemary Batt Gender and Global Change Program Audio-Visual Materials
Batt, Rosemary L.; Cornell University; Gender and Global Change Program
9218939
- Grad Student Events and Information, 2003-2006 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Fall 2004 Schedule (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Cynthia Enloe, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Scope and Contents
  September 30, 2004
- Julia Duany, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  November 16, 2004
- Carline Desire, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  March 31, 2005
- Fall 2006 Schedule (Box 1, Folder 6)
  August 2006
- Opening Reception, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  September 13, 2006
- Carmen Deere, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  September 27, 2006
- Billie Jean Isbell, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  October 11, 2006
- Lourdes Beneria, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  November 1, 2006
- Peace Studies, Elisabeth Wood, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  November 27, 2006
- Neema Kudva, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  March 28, 2007
- GGC/South Asia Program Lecture and Reception, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  April 25, 2007
- GGC Workshop on Afghanistan, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Fall 2007 Posters (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Shabana Azmi, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  August 29, 2007
- Gioconda Herrera, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  September 10, 2007
- Vanita Viswanath, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  September 19, 2007
- Mikki Van Zyl, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  October 24, 2007
- Grad Student Networking and Planning Meeting, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  October 25, 2007
- Louise Lamphere, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  November 1, 2007
- Member List, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  January 1, 2008